Guide to the Alliance for Progressive Action Records, 1990-2003 AIS.2004.15
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Alliance for Progressive Action Records
1990-2003
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Alliance for Progressive Action
AIS.2004.15
28.75 Linear Feet (23 boxes)
The Alliance for Progressive Action (APA) was formed during the spring of 1991 as a coalition of labor and grass roots organizations in Pittsburgh, Pa., that was involved in labor, environmental, social, political and civil rights issues. This collection contains information regarding the organization and activities of the Alliance for Progressive Action.
Access Restrictions
Access to Folder 24 in Box 9 requires a signed confidentiality agreement.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Linda Wambaugh in 1998 and Matt Richards in 2004.
History
The Alliance for Progressive Action (APA) was formed during the spring of 1991 as a coalition of labor and grass roots organizations in Pittsburgh, Pa. APA was involved in labor, environmental, social, political and civil rights issues. The APA became the Pittsburgh chapter of Jobs with Justice, which gave it official status within the AFL-CIO. During the late 1990s into the early 2000s, the organization headed campaigns to create a living wage for workers in Allegheny County, block the privatization of public television in Pittsburgh and create a police review board.
Previous Citation
Alliance for Progressive Action Records, 1990-2003, AIS.2004.15, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains information regarding the organization and activities of the Alliance for Progressive Action. Included are extensive documents regarding the Living Wage Campaign in western Pennsylvania, as well as the organization of a citizen's police review board. Clippings regarding the movement to block the privatization of WQEX and fundraising opportunities are also present.
Related Material
Thomas Merton Center Records, 1971-2004, AIS.1982.19, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Social justice; Living wage movement -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Minutes (Administrative records); Activists; Publications; Social action; Correspondence; Labor; Public television -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Jobs with Justice. Pittsburgh Chapter; Alliance for Progressive Action; WQED (Television station: Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- Administrative Code Committee Meeting, April 11, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Living Wage Steering Committee Sign In Sheets (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Living Wage Planning Meeting, July 12, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- City Public Meeting, May 8, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Democratic Policy Committee, May 3, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Living wage Campaign Steering Committee Meetings, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 6-24)
- Research Committee (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Organizing Committee, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 26-31)
- Living Wage Related Events, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- "Train the Trainers" Packet Originals (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Pittsburgh Post-Gazette Forum Clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
- Signed Living Wage Covenant (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Outreach Program for Endorsing Organizations (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Living Wage Campaign Endorser Newsletter (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Blank Endorsement Forms (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Child Care Organizing (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Button Orders (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Blank Sign-In Sheets (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Living Wage Campaign Standard Literature (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Blank Time Sheets (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Webpage Information (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Pittsburgh Association for the Education of Young Children (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Completed Sign-In Sheets (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Ron Francis, Living Wage Bill (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Living Wage Ordinances in Los Angeles, Minnesota, San Jose and San Antonio (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Laws and Resolutions (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Q&A Ricciardi Legislation (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Living Wage Legislation for Allegheny County: An Analysis of Service Contracting (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Key Provisions of Draft Living Wage Bill for Allegheny County (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Living Wage Code Provisions (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Living Wage Campaign Additions (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Voice for Workers by SEIU 585, March-April 2000 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Living Wage Wars (Box 1, Folder 57)
- "Poverty and Race" Poverty and Race Research Action Council (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Teaching on the Living Wage from Selected Catholic Documents (Box 1, Folder 59)
- "Living Wage urged for Church Employees" Article (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Religious Institutions and the Living Wage (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Labor in the Pulpits Labor Day Organizing Kit (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Actions for Congregations in Living Wage Coalitions (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Western Pennsylvania Living Wage Campaign, the Importance of Living Wage for Women (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Living Wage Campaign Sustainers (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Living Wage Campaign Letterhead (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Correspondence, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Living Wage Campaign Financial Contributors (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Commonly Asked Questions (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Living Wage Committee Endorsers, April 24, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Media Guide (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Key Benchmarks (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Living Wage for Human Service Provider (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Religious Institutions and Living Wage (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Petition, Allegheny County/Pittsburgh (Box 1, Folder 75-76)
- Petition Dos and Don'ts (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Petitioning Report Form (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Elected Officials (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Living Wage Committee Petition Circulars (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Draft, "The Proposed Living Wage Ordinance in Allegheny County: The impact on Service Contractor Employees and Contract Costs" by Steven H. Lopez (Box 1, Folder 81)
- Ralph Bangs Summary (Box 1, Folder 82)
- Ralph Bangs' Living Wage Report, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- Ralph Bangs' Testimony, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 84)
- Living Wage Campaign Newsletters, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 85-91)
- Press Releases, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 92)
- Jobs with Justice (Box 1, Folder 93)
- Just Harvest, October 2000 (Box 1, Folder 94)
- "Its Your Money, Its Your Vote" Citizens' Budget Campaign (Box 1, Folder 95)
- Public Service Accountability (Box 1, Folder 96)
- 2030 Center Campaign (Box 1, Folder 97)
- Related Actions (Box 1, Folder 98)
- Pittsburgh Tribune Article, "Religious Leaders Put Out Call for No Privatization", March 25, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 99)
- Popular Economics Workshop (Box 1, Folder 100-103)
- City of Pittsburgh Living Wage, Mayor Murphy Attack, December 2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Living Wage Campaign Information, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Activity Logs, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees Strike (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Retail Worker Rights Project (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Individual Member Renewals, October 2002 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Organizational Renewals, October 2002 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Membership Lists (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Citizens for Consumer Justice Social Security Event, July 23, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Representative David Levdansky Memo, November 2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Guy Tumolo Draft Living Wage Bill (Box 2, Folder 11)
- ACORN National Living Wage Campaign (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Information for Pittsburgh Council Members (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Part-Time Information (Box 2, Folder 14)
- City of Pittsburgh Living Wage Part-Time Budget Numbers, December 2001 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Allegheny County "Union Neutrality Ordinance", December 2001 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- City of Pittsburgh Contract Information (Box 2, Folder 17)
- County Voter Referendum Information (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Media Tracking Information (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Position Paper (Box 2, Folder 20)
- HERE Local 57, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Rick Schwartz's Union Neutrality (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Living Wage Committee (Box 2, Folder 23)
- County Part-Time (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Allegheny County Budget and Finance, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Endorsement Forms (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Alliance for Progressive Action Founding Conference, May 1991 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Draft Statements of Purpose (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Alliance for Progressive Action Conference, April 1992 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Proposals (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Minutes (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Minutes and Notes (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Memos (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Press Releases (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Member and Mailing Lists (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Mass Mailings (Box 2, Folder 37)
- APA Update! (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Logo (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Other Organizations (Box 2, Folder 40)
- APA Financial Reports and Draft Budgets (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Clippings, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- City and Bills (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Living Wage Bills (Box 2, Folder 44)
- City Living Wage Legislation (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Email Correspondence, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Newsletters, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- QED News, 1997, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
- Christian Television, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- John McCain Clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
- Editorials, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
- Op-Ed Clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
- Letters to the Editor, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
- County Contract Information (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
- Estimates of Non-Profit Impact, April 2000 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Keystone Research Center Proposal to Ferlo for Living Wage Campaign City Research (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Fifty Highest Paid Executives, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Mental Health and Mental Retardation Research (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Pittsburgh ad Allegheny County Finances, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Corporate Accountability (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Pennsylvania AFL-CIO Convention Work (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Pennsylvania AFL-CIO Thirty-Third Constitutional Convention, Officer's Report (Box 4, Folder 10)
- AFL-CIO Sign-Ins (Box 4, Folder 11)
- AFL-CIO and Living Wage (Box 4, Folder 12)
- AFL-CIO Journals, Pennsylvania (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Impacts of the Living Wage Campaign in Pittsburgh, Executive Summary (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Melanie's Files, Living Wage Campaign in the City, December 1998 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Financial Impact Analysis Prepared by David Miller (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Public Hearing on Living Wage, October 29, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Proposed Ordinance from Western Pennsylvania Living Wage Campaign (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Ricciardi Ordinance and Amendments (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Economic Education, Just Economics (Box 4, Folder 20)
- ACORN (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Jobs with Justice (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Labor Party Information (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Regional Industrial Development Corporation of Southwestern Pennsylvania (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Economic Policy Institute, Facts at a Glance (Box 4, Folder 25)
- "Choosing the High Road", Responsible Wealth (Box 4, Folder 26)
- City Testimony, May 8, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- City Public Hearing Sign-In (Box 4, Folder 28)
- City Council Memo and Summary, May 15, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- City Council, May 21, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- City Council Thank You and Contract Information, June 13, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- City Legislation (Box 4, Folder 32)
- City Public Hearing Speakers List, May 8, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- City Meeting, May 16, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Letters Generated to City Council (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Districts, Zip Codes (Box 4, Folder 36)
- County Speakers List, May 21, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Biography, Ron Francis District 1 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- District 1 and 2 Information (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
- Biography, Jan Rae District 2 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- District 3 Information (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Biography, Tom Shumaker District 3 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- District 4 Information (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Biography, Eileen Wagner District 4 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- District 5 Information (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Biography, Vince Gastgeb District 5 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- District 6 and 7 Information (Box 4, Folder 48-49)
- Biography, Rick Schwartz District 7 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- District 8 Information (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Biography, Charles Martoni District 8 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Biography, Richard Olasz District 9 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- District 9 and 10 Information (Box 4, Folder 54-55)
- Biography, James Simms District 10 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- District 11 Information (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Biography, Rich Fitzgerald District 11 (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Living Wage Clippings, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
- Clippings, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Terms of Debate Clippings, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
- Clippings, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Newsletters, 1997-2001 (Box 5, Folder 7-11)
- Jim Roddey Clippings (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Related Clippings, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 13-15)
- Living Wage Campaign Clippings, May 2000 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Op-Ed Clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 17-18)
- Letters to the Editor, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- News Clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
- Debbie Gibbond Letters to Allegheny County Council (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Living Wage Survey Non-Profits (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Living Wage Clippings, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 24-25)
- District 12 Information (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Biography, Wayne Fontana District 12 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- District 13 Information (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Biography, Joe Natoli District 13 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Districts At Large (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Biography, Dave Fawcett At Large (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Democrat Councilmember Mailing, July 2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Councilmember Mailing, September 13, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Candidate Pledge, Pittsburgh and Allegheny County (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Primary, May 18, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Westmoreland County Candidate Pledge, Western Pennsylvania Living Wage Campaign (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Recorder/Report Form for Candidate Meetings (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Possible District Activities (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Election Day, November 1999 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Objectives and Process for Candidate Meetings (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Candidate Pledge/Living Wage Flyer (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Jim Roddey (Box 6, Folder 17-19)
- Living Wage Pull Work, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- County Committee Meeting, November 20, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- County Council Living Wage Committee Meeting, November 14, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- County Living Wage Committee, May 31, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- County Public Hearing, May 12, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Allegheny County Council Meeting, January 16, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Affirmation of Oaths Ceremony for Inaugural County Council, January 3, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Allegheny County Council Meetings, December 5, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 27-45)
- Living Wage Campaign Meeting, July 26, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 46-48)
- Proposed Administrative Code for Allegheny County (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Westmoreland County Petitions (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Other County Petitions (Box 6, Folder 51)
- Primary Polling Petitions, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Living Wage Campaign Signed Petitions (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Election Petitions, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 54)
- Popular Economics Workshop Coverpage (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Completed Workshop Report Forms (Box 6, Folder 56)
- Completed Evaluations (Box 6, Folder 57)
- Record of Workshop Presentation (Box 6, Folder 58)
- Completed Workshop Presentations (Box 6, Folder 59)
- Completed Sign-In Sheets (Box 6, Folder 60)
- Living Wage Campaign, Talking Points Explanation (Box 6, Folder 61)
- Volunteer Survey of Experience (Box 6, Folder 62)
- Volunteer Pledge Sheet (Box 6, Folder 63)
- Fast Track/Free Trade Area of the Americas (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Fast Track Letters to the Editor (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Editorials, 1997-2002 (Box 7, Folder 3-7)
- Op-Ed Clippings, 1998-2001 (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
- Anti-Living Wage Letter to the Editor (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Letters to the Editor, 1997-2002 (Box 7, Folder 11-15)
- Training Articles (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Pitt News, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- AK Steel Action Articles, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- General Clippings (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Living Laws Around the Country Breakdown (Box 7, Folder 20)
- ACORN Conferences (Box 7, Folder 21-27)
- Detroit Study on Living Wage and Non-Profits (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Baltimore Living Wage (Box 7, Folder 29-32)
- Boston Living Wage (Box 7, Folder 33)
- California Living Wage (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Chicago Living Wage (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Cleveland Living Wage Campaign (Box 7, Folder 36-37)
- Living Wage Campaign National Contracts (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Denver Living Wage (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Duluth Living Wage (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Houston Minimum Wage (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Kansas City Living Wage Campaign (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Los Angeles Living Wage Campaign (Box 7, Folder 43-49)
- Minneapolis/St. Paul Living Wage Campaign (Box 7, Folder 50)
- Minnesota Living Wage Campaign (Box 7, Folder 51)
- Minneapolis, Oakland and Labor Language (Box 7, Folder 52)
- New Haven, Connecticut (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Philadelphia Living Wage Campaign (Box 7, Folder 54)
- Portland Living Wage (Box 7, Folder 55)
- San Jose, CA (Box 7, Folder 56)
- Keystone Research Center Executive Summary, May 4, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 57)
- Keystone Research Center Impact Study (Box 7, Folder 58)
- Research Committe Information (Box 7, Folder 59)
- Living Wage Campaign, Local Research (Box 7, Folder 60)
- Living Wage Research (Box 7, Folder 61)
- Pennsylvania Association for Volunteerism, The 12th Annual State Conference on Volunteerism, June 23-25, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Western Pennsylvania Living Wage Campaign Media Coverage, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Western Pennsylvania Living Wage Campaign Economic Analysis, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Western Pennsylvania Living Wage Campaign Pittsburgh Ordinance, Q&A and Talking Points, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Western Pennsylvania Living Wage Campaign Brochure Drafts, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Western Pennsylvania Living Wage Campaign Organizational Newsletter Coverage (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Western Pennsylvania Living Wage Campaign Pittsburgh Ordinance, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
- Western Pennsylvania Living Wage Campaign, National Contracts and Consults (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Living Wage Campaign, Train the Trainers (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
- Living Wage Campaign Organizing Committee (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Living Wage Committee Education (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Request to Speak Signed Sheets, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Kick Off Event Mailing, March 20, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Living Wage Campaign Research (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Endorser Mailing, January 30, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Living Wage Meeting, May 29, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Steering Committee Meetings, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 19-22)
- Living Wage Campaign, Media and Public Relations Committee (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Living Wage Campaign, Newsletter Committee (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Living Wage Campaign Petitioners (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Social Work Research Project, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Living Wage Referendum Survey, June 3, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Position Papers, February 2002 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Organization Survey, January 25, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Living Wage Ordinances (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Alliance for Progressive Action Webpage (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Organizing for Our Future, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 32-37)
- Membership, 1993-1995 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
- Membership Renewal Letters and Notes (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Attorney List and Halloween Party (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Member Survey (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Alliance for Progressive Action BBQ, July 29, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Alliance for Progressive Action 2nd Birthday Party, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Kuntu Theatre (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Board Advance (Box 9, Folder 9)
- APA Board Minutes (Box 9, Folder 10)
- APA Finances (Box 9, Folder 11)
- APA Agendas and Notices (Box 9, Folder 12)
- APA Founding Papers (Box 9, Folder 13)
- APA Attendance (Box 9, Folder 14)
- APA Mission and By-Laws (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Direct Action Response Team (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Conference, April 11, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- APA-United Way Pledge Forms (Box 9, Folder 19)
- APA Open House (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Non-Profit Incubator Projects (Box 9, Folder 22)
- APA Personnel (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Carmen A. Perez [RESTRICTED] (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Balanced Budget Amendment (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Campaign for a New Tomorrow (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Citizen Budget Campaign (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Independent Politics Summit (Box 9, Folder 28)
- Cuba Coalition (Box 9, Folder 29)
- PA Alliance for Democracy (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Conference Notes (Box 9, Folder 31)
- Washington DC Statement (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Domestic Violence (Box 9, Folder 33)
- Gang Peace Council (Box 9, Folder 34)
- No Dice (Box 9, Folder 35)
- Gay Rights Information (Box 9, Folder 36)
- Mumia Abu-Jamal (Box 9, Folder 37)
- Independent Political Action (Box 9, Folder 38)
- Health Care (Box 9, Folder 39)
- March on Washington (Box 9, Folder 40)
- Newsletter, September 1995 (Box 9, Folder 41)
- Save the Family Conference (Box 9, Folder 42)
- North American Free Trade Agreement (Box 9, Folder 43)
- NABISCO and Pittsburgh Press (Box 9, Folder 44)
- Persad Center (Box 9, Folder 45)
- Oral History Project (Box 9, Folder 46)
- Pittsburgh Together (Box 9, Folder 47)
- Pennsylvania Human Relations Commission Advisory Committee (Box 9, Folder 48)
- Pro Choice List (Box 9, Folder 49)
- QED Accountability Project (Box 9, Folder 50)
- Social Action Fair (Box 9, Folder 51)
- Veterans for Peace (Box 9, Folder 52)
- Welfare (Box 9, Folder 53-54)
- APA Working File, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- APA Executive Committee, 1991-1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- APA Membership, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- APA Newsletter, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous APA Materials (Box 10, Folder 5)
- APA Newsletters (Box 10, Folder 6)
- APA Ad Hoc Committee (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Labor in the Pulpit, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Religion and Labor Council, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Letter to James Roddey regarding Trip Oliver, October 5, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Faith Meeting Organizing, July 30, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Living Wage Faith Committee Meeting, October 1, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Faith Mailings, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Faith Meeting, July 1, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Living Wage Committee Prayer Vigil, August 22-23, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Low Wage Family Profile (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Living Wage Campaign Research, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Labor Day Living Wage Campaign, Faith Outreach, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Living Wage Campaign, Presby Work (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Privatization Reports by Steven Lopez (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Election Week Polls, Living Wage Campaign, November 1999 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Living Wage Campaign, Candidate Pledge Press Conference, March 10, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Living Wage Campaign Worker Organizing (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Living Wage Campaign Petition Drive (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Labor Day, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 18-19)
- Living Wage Campaign Steering Committee Meeting, 2000-2002 (Box 11, Folder 20-23)
- Living Wage Campaign Development Committee (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Ralph Bangs Summary and Testimony (Box 11, Folder 25)
- UE Convention Living Wage Campaign Action (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Union Cities (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Union No Strike (Box 11, Folder 28)
- Steering Committee, 1998-2001 (Box 11, Folder 29-30)
- Religious Information (Box 11, Folder 31)
- Pittsburgh Religious Task Force (Box 11, Folder 32)
- Julie Religious Mini-Packet (Box 11, Folder 33)
- Living Wage Campaign Religious Outreach (Box 11, Folder 34)
- Religious Institutions and Living Wage (Box 11, Folder 35)
- Lutheran Living Wage Outreach (Box 11, Folder 36)
- Rothermel and Drohan Letter, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 37)
- APA Board Meetings, 1995-2001 (Box 12)
- Petition to Vote on the Creation of a Police Accountability Board, 1997 (Box 13, Item 1)
- Newspaper Clippings regarding Mental Health (Box 13, Item 2)
- Newspaper Clippings Regarding Police Review Board (Box 13, Item 3)